Guide to the Barbaralee Diamonstein-Spielvogel Collection, 1876-2020 and undated, bulk 1950-2020 RL.10006
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Historic Preservation Project Files, 1912-2020
  - Friends of the High Line, 2003-2013
    - Summer benefit, 2007 (Box 473)
    - Photographs, 2009 (Box 473)
    - General materials, 2010 (Box 473)
    - General materials, 2010-2011 (Box 473)
    - Correspondence, 2012 (Box 473)
    - Media, 2012-2013 (Box 473)
    - Correspondence, 2013 (Box 473)
    - General printed materials and fundraising, 2006-2014 (Box 148)
  - Historic Landmarks Preservation Center, 1956-2020
    Materials related to Diamonstein-Spielvogel's ongoing role as Chair of the Historic Landmarks Preservation Center where she spearheaded the Cultural Medallion program that recognizes buildings associated with distinguished New Yorkers involved in the arts, sciences, the law, business, education, sports and politics. Includes but is not limited to reports, clippings, correspondence, audiovisual materials, printed matter, and notes.
    Divided into two subseries, Administrative and General Files and Cultural Medallions. Both subseries are arranged chronologically. While files for specific Cultural Medallions are arranged chronologically by the approximate date of their installation, they may contain research materials or correspondence from dates prior to the date of installation. Undated materials are at the end of each subseries. Original folder titles have been retained.
    - Administrative and General Files, 1956-2018
      - Organization research materials, 1956-1977 (Box 474)
      - New York Times articles, 1987-2011 (Box 474)
      - General files, 1988-2004 (Box 474)
      - Designation reports, 1991 (Box 474)
      - Technical files, 1992-2000 (Box 474)
      - Manifestations, annual reports, 1994, 2001 (Box 474)
      - Board responses, 1995 (Box 474)
      - Charter, 1995 (Box 474)
      - General files, 1995-2000 (Box 474)
      - Office basics, 1995-1998 (Box 474)
      - Press clippings, 1995 (Box 474)
      - Benefit proposal: One Central Park West/Donald Trump, 1996 (Box 475)
      - Internal Revenue Service status, 1996 (Box 475)
      - New York State Museum questionnaires, 1996-1999 (Box 475)
      - Correspondence, 1997 (Box 475)
      - Kaplan correspondence, 1997 (Box 475)
      - New York City Centennial, 1997-1998 (Box 475)
      - Correspondence, 1998 (Box 475)
      - Design at the Millenium, 1998 (Box 475)
      - Design at the Millenium/ Guild Hall Symposium, 1998 (Box 475)
      - Form letter, 1998 (Box 475)
      - Greenspace Symposium, 1998 (Box 475)
      - Landmarks planning, 1998 (Box 475)
      - Manhattan Magazine, 1999 (Box 475)
      - Ninety-Second Street YMCA, 1998 (Box 475)
      - Opening Symposium, 1998 (Box 475)
      - Panel: "Landmarks - Help or Hindrance," 1998 (Box 475)
      - Streetscape as landmark, 1998 (Box 475)
      - Clippings, 1999 (Box 476)
      - Correspondence, 1999 (Box 476)
      - Cultural Laureates, 1999 (Box 476)
      - Cultural Laureates at Russian Tea Room, 1999 (Box 476)
      - Cultural Laureates biographies, 1999, 2 folders (Box 476)
      - Cultural Laureates prints, 1999 (Box 476)
      - Financial statement, 1999 (Box 476)
      - Landmarks of New York III exhibit, New School, 1999 (Box 476)
      - Russian Tea Room benefit, 1999 (Box 476)
      - Russian Tea Room contract, 1999 (Box 476)
      - Russian Tea Room ticket sales, 1999, folder 1 of 3 (Box 476)
      - Russian Tea Room ticket sales, 1999, folder 2-3 of 3 (Box 477)
      - Senator Goodman fund request, 1999 (Box 477)
      - Sotheby's sale of landmark photographs, 1999 (Box 477)
      - Piccirilli Studio, 1999 (Box 477)
      - General files, 2000-2006, 4 folders (Box 477)
      - Board meeting, December 10, 2001 (Box 478)
      - Conde Nast Travelers' Environmental award, 2002 (Box 478)
      - Donations, 2002 (Box 478)
      - Internships, 2002 (Box 478)
      - Correspondence, 2002-2003 (Box 478)
      - Tax papers, 2003 (Box 478)
      - Correspondence, 2004 (Box 478)
      - Landmarks of New York IV Correspondence, 2004 (Box 478)
      - Landmarks of New York IV Drafts, colors, 2004 (Box 478)
      - Landmarks of New York V, exhibit at Jay Heritage Center, 2013 (Box 478)
      - Tax document, 2004 (Box 478)
      - Correspondence, notes, 2005 (Box 478)
      - Fortieth anniversary New York landmarks legislation, 2005 (Box 478)
      - Financials, 2006 (Box 478)
      - Celebrating New York Landmarks, 2010 (Box 479)
      - Correspondence, 2010 (Box 479)
      - NYC Landmarks Preservation Law, 45th anniversary, 2010 (Box 479)
      - Street sign project, 2010-2012 (Box 479)
      - Correspondence, 2011 (Box 479)
      - Materials, 2011 (Box 479)
      - Scrabble Street sign project/ Daniel Promotion, 2011 (Box 479)
      - Grants, 2012 (Box 479)
      - John Jay Heritage Center, 2012 (Box 479)
      - John Jay Heritage Center, 2013 (Box 616)
      - Google Cultural Institute Project materials, 2013-2015 (Box 604)
      - Google Cultural Institute Project materials, 2013-2015 (Box 618)
      - Application for landmark status, undated (Box 479)
      - Ladies' Mile Neighborhood, undated (Box 479)
      - Photographs and negatives, undated (Box 479)
      - Saint Bartholomew's Church, undated (Box 479)
      - Bodman Foundation grant, 2012 (Box 618)
      - Insurance, 2011 (Box 618)
      - WNET Treasures of New York film grant, 2014-2015 (Box 618)
      - General correspondence and organizational forms, 2013 (Box 76)
      - HLPC tax forms, 2014 (Box 76)
      - Landmarks of New York exhibit tour in China, 2016 (Box 76)
      - Art Deco, Journal of the Art Deco Society of New York, 2016 (Box 639)
      - Designations List, 2013 (Box 76)
      - Correspondence, 2017 (Box 627)
      - General materials and correspondence, including cultural medallions research, 2018-2019 (Box 649)
    - NYC Landmarks 50 Alliance, 1988-2020
      - 49th Anniversary of the NYC Landmarks Law (Box 618)
      - NYC Landmarks 50 Alliance, 2013-2014 and undated, 2 folders (Box 604)
      - NYC Landmarks 50 Alliance, 2013-2017; 4 folders (Box 639)
      - NYC Landmarks 50 Alliance auction, 1988; 2013 (Box 639)
      - NYC Landmarks 50 Alliance cocktail reception, 2014 April (Box 639)
      - NYC Landmarks 50 Alliance events, 2013-2017 (Box 639)
      - NYC Landmarks 50 Alliance Advisory Committee project list, 2013 (Box 639)
      - NYC Landmarks 50 Alliance exhibit, 2014-2017 (Box 639)
      - NYC Landmarks 50 Alliance meeting agendas, 2012-2016 (Box 639)
      - NYC Landmarks 50 Alliance meeting sign-in sheets, 2012-2016 (Box 639)
      - NYC Landmarks 50 Alliance members' correspondence, lists, 2012-2013 (Box 639)
      - NYC Landmarks 50 Alliance meetings and correspondence, 2012-2015, 5 folders (Box 619)
      - NYC Landmarks 50+ Alliance New Yorker proposal, 2013 (Box 629)
      - NYC Landmarks 50 Alliance press clippings, 2013-2016 (Box 629)
      - NYC Landmarks 50 Alliance website design, 2013 (Box 629)
      - NYC Landmarks 50 Alliance publicity materials, 2016 (Box 629)
      - Licensing, 2012-2015 (Box 618)
      - 50th Anniversary of the NYC Landmarks Law panel and reception planning, 2015, 2 folders (Box 618)
      - Unflagging Commitment Sotheby's auction fundraiser, 2014 (Box 618)
      - NASDAQ closing bell event, 2015 (Box 618)
      - Queens Museum event, 2013 (Box 618)
      - Advisory Committee, 2012-2013 (Box 618)
      - Clippings, 2012-2015 (Box 618)
      - Invitations for NYC Landmarks 50 Alliance event at Four Seasons Restaurant, April 2015 (Box 76)
      - Alliance members' projects, 2013 (Box 76)
      - Collateral materials from Alliance members, 2013 (Box 76)
      - Invitations and speech at Thurgood Marshall U.S. Courthouse, 2015 (Box 76)
      - The Bowne House Historical Society Anniversary Celebration, 2015 (Box 76)
      - Panel discussion on the economic impact of historic preservation on NYC, 2015 (Box 76)
      - Living Landmarks Exhibition, 2015 (Box 76)
      - Interior Landmarks book, 2015 (Box 76)
      - Preserving our Architectural History panel discussion, 2015 (Box 76)
      - Landmarks 50 events, 2015-2016 (Box 76)
      - Meetings, correspondence, 2015-2016 (Box 76)
      - Correspondence to and from Deborah Bershad, 2013-2014 (Box 76)
      - Correspondence to and from Deborah Bershad, 2015 (Box 76)
      - 50th anniversary celebration materials from Deborah Bershad (Box 76)
      - 50th Anniversary celebration, 2015 (Box 76)
      - Untitled draft re: importance of Landmarks law and historic preservation, 2015 (Box 76)
      - Correspondence, 2012-2013 (Box 76)
      - Meetings, correspondence, 1988-2018; 2 folders (Box 627)
      - Events at the Four Seasons, 2015-2016 (Box 627)
      - Historic Districts Council, 2016 (Box 627)
      - Murray Hill t-shirt, 2015 (Box 627)
      - Posters, 2015-2017 (Tube 1)
      - Posters, 2014-2015 (Tube 2)
      - Meetings, correspondence, materials, 2018-2019; 2 folders (Box 649)
      - Signifier Project proposal, research, 2015 (Box 649)
      - Correspondence, meeting announcements, drafts, 2018-2020 (Box 653)
    - Cultural Medallions, 1995-2020
      - Brooks Atkinson, 1995 (Box 479)
      - Alfred M. Butts, 1995 (Box 479)
      - James Cagney, 1995 (Box 479)
      - Ceremony, September, 1995 (Box 479)
      - Gentleman Jim Corbett, 1995 (Box 479)
      - Hart Crane, 1995 (Box 479)
      - E.E. Cummings, 1995 (Box 479)
      - George Gershwin, 1995 (Box 480)
      - Horace Greeley, 1995 (Box 480)
      - Victor Herbert, 1995 (Box 480)
      - Malvina Hoffman, 1995 (Box 480)
      - Inauguration, 1995 (Box 480)
      - Instructions, 1995 (Box 480)
      - Scott Joplin, 1995 (Box 480)
      - Lists, 1995 (Box 480)
      - Edna St. Vincent Millay, 1995 (Box 480)
      - Edna St. Vincent Millay, 1995 (Box 619)
      - Lady Deborah Moody, 1995 (Box 480)
      - New York City Building, 1995 (Box 480)
      - Frank O'Hara, 1995 (Box 480)
      - Program Announcement, 1995 (Box 480)
      - Sergei Rachmaninoff, 1995 (Box 480)
      - Edward Arlington Robinson, 1995 (Box 480)
      - Harold Ross, 1995 (Box 480)
      - Dorothy Thompson, 1995 (Box 480)
      - Richard Wright/Willa Cather, 1995 (Box 480)
      - Historic districts, 1995-1998 (Box 480)
      - Othmar Ammann, 1996 (Box 480)
      - Marian Anderson, 1996 (Box 480)
      - Approvals and correspondence, 1996-2017 (Box 629)
      - James Baldwin, 1996 (Box 480)
      - Katherine Cornell, 1996 (Box 480)
      - Cecil B. Demille, 1996 (Box 480)
      - Drafts, 1996 (Box 480)
      - Beatrix Ferrand, 1996 (Box 481)
      - Lou Gehrig, 1996 (Box 481)
      - George Grosz/Claudio Arrau, 1996 (Box 481)
      - Harry Houdini, 1996 (Box 481)
      - Jack Kerouac, 1990-1996 and undated, 2 folders (Box 481)
      - Joseph Papp, 1996 (Box 481)
      - Reader's Digest, 1996 (Box 481)
      - Jackie Robinson, 1996 (Box 481)
      - Eleanor Roosevelt, 1996 (Box 481)
      - Texts for May, 1996 (Box 481)
      - Thomas Wright Fats Waller, 1996 and undated (Box 481)
      - Correspondence, 1996-1997 (Box 481)
      - Wystan Hugh Auden, 1997 (Box 481)
      - Description, 1998 (Box 481)
      - John Dewey, 1998 (Box 481)
      - Edna Ferber, 1998 (Box 482)
      - John J. Fitzgerald, 1998 (Box 482)
      - Admiral Bull Halsey, 1998 (Box 482)
      - Charles Ives, 1998 (Box 482)
      - Lists, 1998 (Box 482)
      - Master list, 1998 (Box 482)
      - Henry Miller, 1998 (Box 482)
      - Paul Robertson, 1998 (Box 482)
      - Babe Ruth, 1998 (Box 482)
      - Text - revised, 1998 (Box 482)
      - Andy Warhol, 1998 (Box 482)
      - Correspondence, 1999 (Box 482)
      - Charles Evan Hughes, 1998-1999 (Box 482)
      - In progress, 1999 (Box 482)
      - Marianne Moore, 1999 (Box 482)
      - Plaque nominations, 1999 (Box 482)
      - Roy Wilkins, 1999 (Box 482)
      - Betty Carter, 2000 (Box 482)
      - Allen Ginsberg, 2000 (Box 482)
      - Research, 2000-2001 (Box 482)
      - Senator Daniel Patrick Moynihan place, 2001 (Box 482)
      - Guide: Prototype materials, 2001-2003 (Box 483)
      - Research, 2002 (Box 483)
      - Harold Schonberg, 2003 (Box 483)
      - Negatives, 2004-2005 (Box 483)
      - Copy, 2007 (Box 483)
      - Good Humor Bar, 2007 (Box 483)
      - New York Community Trust, 2009-2010 (Box 483)
      - Project, 2009-2010 (Box 483)
      - Edward Stone, 2010 (Box 483)
      - Articles, 2011 (Box 483)
      - Edith Wharton, 2011 (Box 483)
      - Edith Wharton, 2011 (Box 619)
      - Odetta, 2012 (Box 483)
      - Odetta, 2012 (Box 619, Box 653)
      - Richard Nathaniel Wright, 2012 (Box 483)
      - Richard Nathaniel Wright, 2012 (Box 619)
      - General information and summaries, 2012-2013 (Box 604)
      - Albert Sprague Bard, 2013 (Box 604)
      - Albert Sprague Bard, 2013 (Box 619)
      - George William Curtis, 2013 (Box 604)
      - Miles Davis, 2013 (Box 604)
      - Woody Guthrie, 2013 (Box 604)
      - Woody Guthrie, 2014 (Box 76)
      - Harry L. Hopkins, 2012-2013 (Box 604)
      - Harry L. Hopkins, 2012-2013 (Box 619)
      - Edward Hopper, 2013 (Box 604)
      - Edward Hopper, 2013 (Box 619)
      - Ada Louise Huxtable, 2013 (Box 605)
      - Ada Louise Huxtable, 2013 (Box 76)
      - Lincoln Kirstein, 2013 (Box 605)
      - Lincoln Kirstein, 2013 (Box 619)
      - Edward Koch, 2013 (Box 605)
      - Edward Koch, 2013 (Box 619)
      - Barnett Newman, 2013 (Box 605)
      - Barnett Newman, 2013 (Box 76)
      - Stonewall Riots, 2013 (Box 605)
      - Stonewall Riots, 2013 (Box 76)
      - Chester Allen Arthur, medallion, undated (Box 593)
        Copy of oval medallion installed at location, approximately 12x13".
      - Wynston Hugh Auden, medallion, undated (Box 593)
      - Baruch College, Jane Cotty, undated (Box 483)
      - Fiorello La Guardia, Bronx, undated (Box 483)
      - Form letters, undated (Box 483)
      - Photographs, undated (Box 483)
      - USS Intrepid, undated (Box 483)
      - Correspondence re: Cultural Medallions, 2011-2015, 3 folders (Box 619)
      - Bella Abzug, 2014 (Box 619)
      - Bella Abzug, 2014 (Box 76)
      - Miles Davis, undated (Box 76)
      - Miles Davis, undated (Box 619)
      - Oscar Hijuelos, 2014 (Box 76)
      - Oscar Hijuelos, 2014 (Box 619)
      - Al Hirshfield, 2006 (Box 619)
      - Norris Houghton proposal, undated (Box 619)
      - Sinclair Lewis, 2014 (Box 619)
      - John Vliet Lindsay, 2014 (Box 619)
      - Robert Rauschenberg, 2013 (Box 619)
      - Jonas Salk, 2015 (Box 619)
      - Speech drafts from Cultural Medallion dedication ceremonies, 2013, undated (Box 76)
      - Cultural Medallions survey responses, 2014 (Box 76)
      - Ethel Waters, 2015 (Box 76)
      - Hannah Arendt proposal, 2016 (Box 629)
      - Harper Lee, 2016 (Box 76)
      - Arthur Miller, 2016 (Box 629)
      - Walt Whitman, 2016 (Box 76)
      - Leonard Bernstein, 2017 (Box 629)
      - Pete Seeger, 2014 (Box 76)
      - Merce Cunningham, 2013 (Box 76)
      - George William Curtis, 2013 (Box 76)
      - Albert Bard, 2013 (Box 636)
      - John Purroy Mitchell, 2015 (Box 76)
      - George Gershwin, medallion, undated (Box 632)
      - Harold Lloyd Hopkins, medallion (Box 632)
      - Correspondence, 2017 (Box 636)
      - Franklin and Eleanor Roosevelt, 2017-2018 (Box 636, Box 649)
      - WC Handy, 2017 (Box 636)
      - Jerome Robbins, 2017 (Box 636)
      - Edie Wiindsor, 2017-2018 (Box 636, Box 649)
      - Lorraine Hansberry, 2017 (Box 636)
      - Murray Hill, 2017 (Box 636)
      - Tandy/Cronyn, 2018 (Box 649)
      - Ella Fitzgerald, 2018 (Box 649)
      - Woody Guthrie, 2018 (Box 649)
      - Charles Dana Gibson, 2018 (Box 649)
      - Wallace Stevens, 2018 (Box 649)
      - David Dubrinsky, 2018 (Box 649)
      - Conde Nast, 2018 (Box 649)
      - Merce Cunningham, 2018 (Box 649)
      - General correspondence, drafts, lists of medallions, 2010-2019 (Box 653)
      - Romare Bearden, 2020 (Box 653)
      - Philip Roth, 2019 (Box 653)
    - Notable New Yorkers (book), 2017-2019
      Materials from BLDS and Deborah Bershad's book on the history of the Cultural Medallions program.
      - Research materials, 1990s-2018 (Box 650)
      - Drafts and proofs, 2018; 3 Files (Box 650)
      - Publicity, correspondence, 2018 (Box 650)
      - Diamonstein-Spielvogel, Barbaralee, and Deborah Bershad Addeo (editor). Notable New Yorkers: HPLC Cultural Medallions (hardback copy), 2018 (Box 653)
  - Municipal Art Society, 1975-1993
    Contains general files associated with Diamonstein-Spielvogel's work with the Municipal Art Society, an organization founded in 1893 that advocates for the quality of the built environment through excellence in urban planning, design, preservation, and enhancing public spaces through the arts. Arranged chronologically. Original folder titles have been retained.
    - Awards, 1975-1979, 2 folders (Box 484)
    - Benefit, 1977-1978 (Box 484)
    - Correspondence, minutes and materials, 1982-1983 (Box 484)
    - General files, 1975-1985, 1 folders (Box 484)
    - General files, 1975-1985, 2-5 of 10 files (Box 485)
    - General files, 1975-1985, 6-10 of 10 files (Box 486)
    - General files, 1975-1985 (Oversize-folder 3)
    - Invitation, 1977 (Box 486)
    - Ninetieth birthday, 1981-1982 (Box 486)
    - One hundredth anniversary, 1993 (Box 486)
    - Promotional materials including newsletter, 1981 (Box 595)
  - National Register of Historic Places, 1975; 2010-2012
    Contains official registration or application forms sent by organizations to the National Register of Historic Places, part of a national program to coordinate and support public and private efforts to identify, evaluate, and protect our historic and archaeological resources. Original folder titles have been retained.
    - Registration form, 1975 (Box 487)
    - Registration forms, 2010-2012, 1-5 of 14 folders (Box 487)
    - Registration forms, 2010-2012, 6-9 of 14 folders (Box 488)
    - Registration forms, 2010-2012, 10-14 of 14 folders (Box 489)
  - New York Historic Landmarks Preservation Commission, 1912-2018
    Contains correspondence, reports, notes, memoranda, meeting materials, printed matter, clippings, photographs, and other organizational records related to Diamonstein-Spielvogel's role in the New York Landmarks Preservation Commission where she served as the longest-serving Commissioner from 1972 to 1987. The records reflect the evolution of landmarks laws in general as well as the work of the Landmarks Preservation Commission. Divided into two subseries: Administrative and General Records and Event and Subject Files.
    - Administrative and General Records, 1962-2016
      - General, 1962-1973, 4 folders (Box 490)
      - Calendar items, 1965-1967, 3 folders (Box 491)
      - Correspondence, 1967-1972 (Box 491)
      - Certificates of Appropriateness, 1967-1983 and undated (Box 491)
      - Calendar items, 1968-1969, 3 folders (Box 491)
      - Calendar items, 1970 (Box 492)
      - Memorandum submitted by New York Landmarks Preservation Commission, 1970, 2 folders (Box 492)
      - Board Materials, 1972, 1-3 of 4 folders (Box 492)
      - Board Materials, 1972, 4 folders (Box 493)
      - Calendar items, 1972-1973, 3 folders (Box 493)
      - Correspondence, 1973 (Box 493)
      - Calendar items, 1974-1975, 3 folders (Box 493)
      - Statements and agendas, 1975-1976 (Box 493)
      - General files, 1976-1982, 1 folders (Box 493)
      - General files, 1976-1982, 2-4 of 4 folders (Box 494)
      - Meeting materials, May 11, 1976 (Box 494)
      - Resignation letter to Koch, 1977 (Box 494)
      - Commissioner's Handbook, 1979, 1-2 of 3 folders (Box 494)
      - Commissioner's Handbook, 1979, 3 folders (Box 495)
      - General files, 1979, 2 folders (Box 495)
      - Renovation and designations, 1979, 3 folders (Box 495)
      - Renovations and designations (oversize), 1979 (Oversize-folder 3)
      - Public hearings, 1980 (Box 496)
      - General files, 1981, 1-5 of 8 folders (Box 496)
      - General files, 1981, 6-8 of 8 folders (Box 497)
      - Hearing/meeting materials, February, 1981-1982, 2 folders (Box 497)
      - Certificates of Appropriateness, 1982, 2 folders (Box 497)
      - Commissioner's leaders announcement, 1982-1983 (Box 498)
      - Commissioner's meeting, June 27, 1982 (Box 498)
      - Executive meeting, June 22, 1982 (Box 498)
      - Executive meeting, July 20, 1982 (Box 498)
      - General files, 1982-1983 (Box 498)
      - Meeting materials, 1982 (Box 498)
      - Miscellaneous files, 1982-1983 (Box 498)
      - Nomination, Commissioner, 1982 (Box 498)
      - Renovations, designations, miscellaneous, 1982 (Box 498)
      - Certificates of Appropriateness, 1983, 3 folders (Box 499)
      - Certificates of Appropriateness, designations, 1983 (Box 499)
      - Designation Request Forms, 1983-1984 (Box 499)
      - General files, 1983-1985 (Box 499)
      - Meetings and Certificates of Appropriateness, 1983 (Box 499)
      - Meeting materials, 1983 (Box 499)
      - Public hearings, 1983 (Box 499)
      - Certificates of Appropriateness, New York Historical Society, 1984 (Box 499)
      - Correspondence, 1984 (Box 499)
      - Executive meeting, August, 1984 (Box 499)
      - Hearing/meeting materials, February-March, 1984 (Box 500)
      - Landmarks Nomination Form, 1984 (Box 500)
      - Memoranda, 1984 (Box 500)
      - Certificates of Appropriateness, Inventor's Gate, 1985 (Box 500)
      - Commissioners' review, committee calendar, 1985 (Box 500)
      - General files, 1985, 2 folders (Box 500)
      - Hearing/meeting materials, December, 1985 (Box 500)
      - Landmark New Issues, 1984-1985 (Box 500)
      - Proposed landmark designation, 1985 (Box 500)
      - Public hearings, 1985 (Box 501)
      - Saint Bartholomew's Church, affidavits, 1984-1985 (Oversize-folder 3)
      - Correspondence, 1986 (Box 501)
      - General files, 1986-1988 (Box 501)
      - General files, 1986-1987, Correspondence, 1986-1987 (Box 501)
      - Guidebook supplement, 1986 (Box 501)
      - Hearing/meeting materials, 1986, 1-2 of 6 folders (Box 501)
      - Hearing/meeting materials, 1986, 3-6 of 6 folders (Box 502)
      - Materials for sites under consideration, 1986-1987, 2 folders (Box 502)
      - Meeting materials, 1986 (Box 503)
      - Minutes, 1986-1987 (Box 503)
      - Public hearing, 1986 (Box 503)
      - Executive session, February, 1987 (Box 503)
      - Hearing/meeting materials, February, 1987 (Box 503)
      - Resignation letter, 1987 (Box 503)
      - Responses to resignation, 1987 (Box 503)
      - Guardians of the Cityscape, article by Diamonstein-Spielovgel calling for restructuring of the Landmarks Preservation Commission, 1987 (Box 503)
      - Guardians of the Cityscape, article by Diamonstein-Spielovgel calling for restructuring of the Landmarks Preservation Commission, 1987 (Box 76)
      - Community boards, 1988-1994 (Box 503)
      - Correspondence, 1992-1993 (Box 503)
      - Commission rules, 1994 (Box 503)
      - Landmarks of New York condition reports, 2009, 2 folders (Box 503)
      - Correspondence, 2011-2012 (Box 503)
      - Landmarks Preservation Commission printouts, information, etc., 2012-2013 (Box 148)
      - Manuscript of guidelines, undated (Box 503)
      - Codes and guidelines, undated (Box 503)
      - Clippings, 2015 (Box 76)
      - Correspondence, 2016 (Box 636)
    - Event and Subject Files, 1912-2018
      Specific Commission projects with which Diamonstein-Spielvogel was involved; arranged alphabetically. Original folder titles have been retained.
      - African Burial Ground - The Commons Historic District, 1993-1997 (Box 504)
      - All designated interiors list, 1997 (Box 504)
      - Anthony Campagna estate, West 249th St., 1993 (Box 504)
      - Art Commission of the City of New York application, 1987 (Box 504)